<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Siyue (Sia) Huang</title><link>https://siahuang-818.github.io/authors/author/</link><atom:link href="https://siahuang-818.github.io/authors/author/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Siyue (Sia) Huang</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><image><url>https://siahuang-818.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url><title>Siyue (Sia) Huang</title><link>https://siahuang-818.github.io/authors/author/</link></image><item><title/><link>https://siahuang-818.github.io/authors/author/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://siahuang-818.github.io/authors/author/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was awarded a Bachelor of Arts in Japanese (with a minor in Law) from the University of International Business and Economics (UIBE), Beijing, in July 2023. Since April 2024, I have been pursuing a Master of Laws (LL.M.) at Keio University, Tokyo, with expected completion in April 2026. My graduate research specializes in corporate law with an interdisciplinary focus on the intersection of legal reasoning, linguistic structures, and intelligent systems.
With my cross-cultural legal linguistic proficiency in Chinese, Japanese, English, and Korean, I conduct systematic comparative analyses of fundamental differences between common law and civil law systems, particularly in legislative techniques and judicial interpretation. This empirical research using multilingual legal texts has driven my scholarly investigation into Natural Language Processing (NLP) applications for legal workflows.
To operationalize this interdisciplinary approach, I have developed technical competencies in Python, C#, and computer vision (YOLO), which I applied during research internships at Zhejiang Libiao Robotics (AI-driven automation systems) and the Shanghai Pudong People&amp;rsquo;s Court (computational legal analysis). These experiences demonstrate my commitment to developing technological solutions for emerging challenges at the nexus of law and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>